<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>On the art of digiscoping</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/</link>
    <description>Recent content on On the art of digiscoping</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>24mm binned vs 48mm unbinned</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2024/08/03/24mm-vs-48mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2024/08/03/24mm-vs-48mm/</guid>
      <description>Different pixel outputs The sensor on the 5V is a 48-megapixel sensor, but the largest output is 12-megapixel photos. This is because the sensor combines 4 &amp;lsquo;sensor pixels&amp;rsquo; to produce 1 &amp;lsquo;image pixel&amp;rsquo; in the 24mm mode, a process called pixel binning. This likely results in reduced noise but at the cost of resolution.&#xA;In the 48mm mode, photos are twice as zoomed in, but the output is still 12 megapixels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waders and focus</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2024/07/30/waders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2024/07/30/waders/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I went to eastern Öland to look at waders. It was the first time using the digiscoping setup properly.&#xA;Focus peaking First of all, I&amp;rsquo;m impressed by the ability of the phone to snap into focus despite the scope being out of focus. With digiscoping, you have to guess approximately where the focus of the scope is and let the phone do the final adjusting. Or, if you are using manual focus, you have to see on the phone screen if the photo is in focus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digiscoping vs DSLR camera</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2024/07/29/digiscoping-vs-dslr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2024/07/29/digiscoping-vs-dslr/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the capabilities of a new phone As a birder, getting good photos consistently is really important, as the difference between euphoria and catastrophe often depends on getting documentation that supports your claimed identification. I recently got a new phone and I&amp;rsquo;m curious about its capabilities, both in terms of being able to capture detailed information down to a pixel level, but also in terms of taking aesthetically pleasing photos of birds and their surroundings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/about/</guid>
      <description>A space for the exploration of the capabilities of smartphone digiscoping.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
